Preliminary Guide to the Si Williams Agricultural Papers 1948-1983
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Preliminary Guide to the Si Williams Agricultural Papers
1948-1983
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
MS 1982.13
Williams, Seymour
16.25 Linear feet of shelf space 15 Boxes
The Si Williams Agricultural Papers consist of catalogs, brochures and other materials focused on agriculture and livestock in the Pacific Northwest, predominantly as it relates to sales and marketing.
Seymour (Si) Williams was a livestock auctioneer in Idaho. He worked sales and auctions in the Pacific Northwest, as well as Illinois, Colorado, and South Dakota.
The Si Williams Agricultural Papers consist of catalogs, brochures and other materials focused on agriculture and livestock in the Pacific Northwest, predominantly as it relates to sales and marketing. It also includes a binder with thirty years of Mr. Williams’ field and daily notes and folders containing the history of the Williams family in the Pacific Northwest.
This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Si Williams donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries in 1982 (MS 1982.13).
The repository does not expect to receive additions to this collection.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Williams, Seymour -- Archives.
Livestock -- Northwest, Pacific -- Marketing -- History; Agriculture -- Northwest, Pacific -- History
Agriculture; Idaho; Washington
- Si Williams materials generated as a part of his work as an auctioneer, pictures, narratives and letters, binder with thirty year summary of field and daily notes, Charolais Breeding Ranches, LTD. materials, Breeders Guides., 1948-1977 (Box 1)
- Breeders Association catalogs for Oregon, materials related to agriculture at State College of Washington, Hereford and bull sales in Oregon and Montana, framed photo of Hereford from the Western Charolais Association, Williams family history., 1950-1951 (Box 2)
- Oregon, Texas, and Washington sales brochures about Herefords, with cattle lineage, location, and weight. Documents are primarily from the Western States Angus Association., 1951-1982 (Box 3)
- Catalogs and materials related to the sale of Herefords in Washington and Idaho. Includes document significant to Pullman - the Black Out Farms 4th Annual Production Sale 45 bulls, 42 bred Heifers Pullman WA, November 11th 1967., 1967-1974 (Box 4)
- Catalogs related to the sale of Herefords in Montana, Oregon, Colorado. Additional documents about Washington State Charolais Association., 1968-1969 (Box 5)
- Catalogs related to the sale of Herefords in Washington, Montana, and Idaho., 1959-1967 (Box 6)
- Documents about Hereford sales and auctions. Poster about farm auction sale April 12, 1958. Cattle, horses, equipment available in Boardman, Oregon. Auctioneer Si Williams., 1958-1970 (Box 7)
- Catalogs and materials related to the sale of Herefords in Oregon, Mississippi, and South Dakota., 1970-1973 (Box 8)
- Catalogs related to the sale of Herefords in Washington, Oregon, and Idaho., 1962-1973 (Box 9)
- Catalogs and materials related to the sale of livestock and Herefords in California, Oregon, and Washington., 1951-1963 (Box 10)
- Catalogs and materials related to Angus and Hereford sales in Washington, Idaho, Oregon, and California., 1952-1953 (Box 11)
- Materials concerning Range Bull sales and Hereford sales. Map of Salmon River Estates. Poster for sale of 9 lots on Williams Lake with 25 frontage and 25 view acreage lots, Williams Lake, Salmon Idaho. Materials concern Washington, Idaho, Montana., 1953-1965 (Box 12)
- Catalogs for cattle "Angus" auctions in multiple states, including South Dakota, Illinois, Oregon, and Washington., 1964-1965 (Box 13)
- Catalogs and materials related to livestock sales, loose photographs found in brochures, posters about Hereford sales in Oregon. Documents about Hereford sales, document about Chewack River Ranch, Charolas magazine about beef production, and Si Williams materials genreated as a part of his auctioneer work., 1950-1952; 1954-1955; 1956; 1970; 1983 (Box 14)
- Idaho, Oregon, and Washington documents about the sale of herd bulls, range bulls, poster from the Dalles livestock auction Dalles, Oregon March 28th, 1956., 1955-1956 (Box 15)